让我们继续处理文本。
Let's keep working with text.
在本次讲座中，我们将学习如何创建列表
And in this lecture, we will learn how to create lists
带有要点和数字。
with bullet points and also with numbers.
我所说的列表基本上是
And what I mean by list is basically
就像我们在这里的项目符号列表一样，
like a list of bullet points, like we have here,
也像一个带数字的有序列表，
and also like an ordered list with numbers,
就像这里有 1、2、3 个有序元素。
like here with 1, 2, 3 ordered elements.
好的。所以这在 HTML 中很容易做到。
All right. So that is very easy to do in HTML.
那么让我们看看如何。
So let's see how.
所以从编号列表开始，这里是这个，
So starting with the numbered list, so this one here,
它在我们文本这一部分的末尾。
it is here at the end of this section of our text.
所以在什么是 HTML 部分。
So in the What is HTML part.
所以我们有这个段落，然后我们有这个段落，
So we have this paragraph, then we have this paragraph,
然后我们实际上还有另一段
and then we actually have another paragraph there
我们错过了。
that we missed.
在那之后，我们有了清单。
And then after that, we have the list.
因此，让我们获取所有这些内容。
So let's get all of this content.
这是三个列表项，
So these are the three list items,
这就是缺失的段落。
and that is the missing paragraph.
好的。
Okay.
只需将所有内容粘贴到此处即可。
Just paste all of that here.
现在我将简单地将这个元素包装在 p 中。
And now I will simply wrap this element inside of a p.
所以我们有这个段落。
And so there we have the paragraph.
所以我们这里的一切结构都很好，
So we have everything nicely structured here,
现在让我们开始列表。
and now let's start the list.
所以开始一个有序列表的元素，
So the element to start a ordered list,
这就是所谓的带有数字的列表，
which is what a list with numbers is called,
我们使用 ol 元素。
we use the ol element.
所以像这样。
So like this.
所以 ol 代表有序列表。
And so ol stands for ordered list.
我们打开它，当然，
And we open it, so of course,
我们还需要关闭元素。
we also need to close the element.
好的。
Okay.
现在让我们在这里给我们一些空间，因为实际上
Now let's give us some space here because actually
对于列表中的每个元素，
for each of the elements of the list,
我们需要在有序列表中创建一个元素。
we need to create an element inside of the ordered list.
因此，我们使用 li 元素，
And so for that, we use the li element,
代表列表项。
which stands for list item.
所以列出项目，
So list item,
打开它，
open it,
并关闭它，
and close it,
然后让我们抓取这个内容。
and then let's grab this content.
所以开始标签，让我们实际剪掉它。
So the opening tag, let's cut it actually.
好的。
Okay.
那我也要剪这两个
Then I'm going to cut these two as well
并将它们粘贴在这里。
and paste them down here.
然后简单地将它包装在更多的 li 元素中。
And then simply wrap it inside some more li elements.
再说一次，li 代表列表项，
So again, li stands for list item,
而 ol 代表有序列表。
while ol stands for ordered list.
在这里，我使用 tab 键给它一些缩进
Here, I'm giving it some indentation using the tab key
只是为了让它们在视觉上都作为子元素对齐
just so that they are visually all aligned as child elements
的有序列表。
of the ordered list.
所以也许你注意到我是如何使用这些术语的
So maybe you noticed how I'm using the terms
子元素和父元素。
child elements and parent elements.
因此，每当我们在另一个元素中包含一个元素时，
So whenever we have an element inside of another,
基本上另一个元素的容器是父元素。
basically the container of another element is the parent.
所以在这种情况下，这就是有序列表。
So in this case, that's the ordered list.
然后是父级内部的元素
And then the elements that are inside the parent
是子元素。
are the child elements.
好吧，但让我们回到这里重新加载它。
All right, but let's go back here and reload it.
确实有我们的有序列表。
And indeed there is our ordered list.
好的。
Nice.
所以谷歌Chrome浏览器理解我们的代码
So the Google Chrome browser understands our code
并且知道它应该渲染它
and knows that it should render it
作为有序数字的列表。
as a list of ordered numbers.
所以1、2、3。
So 1, 2, 3.
当然，它会自动应用这些数字
And of course, it then automatically applies these numbers
无需我们做任何事情。
without us having to do anything.
如果我们添加另一个元素，
And if we added another element,
假设我们甚至会在开头添加它，
let's say we would even add it here at the beginning,
那将成为第一个元素.
that would then become the first element.
哦对不起。
Oh, sorry.
那么，正如我所说，
So that would then, as I was saying,
成为第一个元素。
become the first element.
事实上，现在我们有四个
And indeed, now we have four of them
这是第一个，
and this one is the first,
但是这个我们不想要，让我们摆脱它。
but this one we don't want, let's get rid of it.
好的。
Nice.
这就是清单之一。
So that is one of the lists.
然后另一个是这里的这个，
And then the other one is this one here in the,
为什么要学习 HTML 部分。
Why should you learn HTML part.
再说一次，这里还有一些其他的内容，
And again, there is some other content here,
所以让我们继续抓住这一切
so let's go ahead and grab all of this
从这里的内容文件。
from this content file here.
所以这是标题，
So this is the heading,
现在我们需要所有这些。
and now we need all of this.
复制和粘贴。
Copy and paste.
所以再一次，
And so once again,
我将从将这些包装成段落开始。
I will start by wrapping these into paragraphs.
所以也许你开始看到
And so maybe you are starting to see
我们真的在创造一个漂亮整洁的结构
that we are really creating a nice and tidy structure
其中每条内容都在某个元素内。
where each piece of content is inside of some element.
所以我们没有任何文字漂浮在周围
So we don't have like any text floating around
只是在身体内部而不是在一个元素中，对吧？
just inside of the body without being in an element, right?
我们总是在创造一个很好的结构，其中每个元素
We always are creating a nice structure where each element
具有一定的意义。
has a certain meaning.
例如，所有这些当然都是段落，
So for example, all of these are of course paragraphs,
这就是我们使用 p 元素的原因。
and that's why we use the p element.
而这里的这段内容是一个列表
And this piece of content here is a list
这就是我们使用有序列表元素的原因。
and that's why we use the ordered list element.
所以这本质上是为了赋予一些意义
And so that is essentially to assign some meaning
内容并以合乎逻辑的方式对其进行结构化。
to the content and to structure it in a logical way.
所以这允许网络浏览器显示它
And so this then allows web browsers to display it
以一种有意义的方式。
in a way that makes sense.
但无论如何，现在我们这里有这个内容，
But anyway, now we have this content here,
你想要在这种列表中，
which you want in this kind of list,
就像这里的要点一样。
like bullet points here.
所以我们使用的元素是 ul。
And so the element that we use for that is ul.
ul，也许你可以猜到，代表无序列表。
And ul, maybe you can guess, stands for unordered list.
好吧，让我们在这里关闭它，
All right, let's close it down here,
ul。
ul.
所以一个带有数字的有序列表是 ol，
And so an ordered list with the numbers is ol,
和一个没有数字的，
and the one without numbers,
我们说它是无序的，因为顺序
which we say is unordered because the order
元素无关紧要，
of the elements does not matter,
所以这被称为 ul，它代表无序列表。
so that is then called ul, which stands for unordered list.
但是在列表本身的内部，
But then inside of the list itself,
我们仍然必须使用 li 元素
we still have to use the li element
对于个别项目。
for the individual items.
所以就像以前一样，我们需要包装所有
So just like before, we need to wrap all
将这些不同的内容组成一个 li 元素。
of these different pieces of content into an li element.
所以我们之前已经这样做了，
So we already did that before,
所以我相信你知道该怎么做。
so I'm sure you know how to do it.
也许你看到了它的到来
And maybe you saw it coming that this
对您来说是另一个非常小的编码挑战。
is another very small coding challenge for you.
所以现在暂停视频并做同样的事情
So pause the video now and do exactly the same thing
我们在这里做的。
that we did up here.
因此，将这些项目中的每一个都包装在一个实际的 li 元素中。
So wrap each of these items in an actual li element.
像这样，你可以继续练习写作
and so like this, you can keep practicing writing
你自己的一些HTML。
some HTML on your own.
好的。所以我希望这是一个简单的挑战。
Okay. So I hope that was a simple challenge.
所以让我们在这里快速完成。
And so let's quickly do it here.
好的。
All right.
所以这里的这个实际上有多行。
So this one here actually has multiple lines.
所以到此结束。
So it ends here.
而且你看到这里的格式是完全错误的，
And you see that the formatting here is completely wrong,
但我不担心，因为为此，
but I'm not worrying about that because for that,
我们有 Prettier 的辅助工具，对吧？
we have the helper tool of Prettier, right?
所以 Prettier 照顾f 我们所有的格式，
So Prettier takes care of all our formatting,
但希望你看到没有这种格式，
but hopefully you see that without that formatting,
这看起来一团糟，对吧？
this looks like a complete mess, right?
这很难理解。
It's very hard to understand.
所以比如说这里的这个元素不是子元素
So for example, this element here is not a child element
p，所以这里应该对齐。
of p, so it should be aligned here.
当然，我们可以手动完成，
And we could do that manually, of course,
只需删除这个空间，
simply by deleting this space,
但我们也可以把它留给 Prettier
but we can also just leave it to Prettier
一旦我们保存文件。
once we save the file.
对不起。
Sorry.
在这里，我错过了结束斜线。
And here I'm missing the closing slash.
现在，正如我所说，当我保存文件时，
And now, as I was saying, as I save the file,
然后 Prettier 施展魔法
then Prettier does its magic
并且在这里很好地格式化了我们的元素。
and nicely formatted here our elements.
由于某种原因，现在我们这里也有这个空段落，
Now we also have this empty paragraph here for some reason,
所以也许我之前在这里犯了一些错误，
so maybe I did some mistake here earlier,
所以让我们删除它并再次保存它。
so let's just delete it and save it again.
现在，当我们来到我们的页面时，确实，
And now as we come here to our page, then, indeed,
我们在这里有我们漂亮的无序列表。
we have our nice unordered list down here.
伟大的。
Great.
所以创建列表是编写 HTML 的另一个重要部分。
So creating lists is another important part of writing HTML.
我们一直在使用它。
We use this all the time.
所以我希望你在这次讲座中玩得开心
And so I hope that you had fun with this lecture
因为这是一件非常重要的事情。
because it was quite an important one.
所以在你继续之前，
So before you move on,
请务必查看我们刚刚在这里所做的事情。
please make sure to review what we just did here.
也想了一些
And also think a little bit about some
我之前说的那些，
of the things I said earlier,
比如每个元素都有不同的含义，
such as the fact that each element has a different meaning,
而且我们需要使用这些元素
and also that we need to use these elements
构建我们的内容。
to structure our content.
所以我们不能简单地把我们所有的文字都转储到这里
So we cannot simply just dump all of our text here
进入正文并收工。
into the body text and call it a day.
如果我们这样做了，
If we did that,
根本没有结构和逻辑。
there would be no structure and no logic at all.
所以我只是在这里删除了一些空白段落。
So I just deleted some empty paragraph here.
我只是想告诉你会发生什么
I just wanted to show you what happens
如果我选择所有这些。
if I select all of this.
所以基本上在这里复制粘贴。
So copy paste here, basically.
所以如果我把它贴在这里。
So if I take it and just paste it down here.
所以给它一个保存，
So give it a save and,
好吧，你看到它现在都是一大块文本
well, you see that it's now all one big blob of text
而 HTML 并不真正关心任何空白。
and HTML doesn't really care about any white space.
所以这里的任何换行符，
So any of these line breaks here,
它们都与 HTML 无关。
they're all irrelevant to HTML.
所以如果我们尝试加载这个，
So if we try to load this,
你看（笑）根本没有结构。
you see (laughs) that there is no structure at all.
所以一切都只是一大行文字，是的，
So everything is just one huge line of text and yeah,
就是这样，没有结构，没有意义。
that's it, there is no structure, there is no meaning.
基本上什么都没有。
There is nothing basically.
所以我希望这个小例子能告诉你
And so I hope that this small example showed you
基本上包裹所有部分的重要性
the importance of basically wrapping all pieces
元素内部的内容
of content inside of an element
这实际上赋予了该内容一些意义，好吗？
that actually gives that content some meaning, okay?
但这样一来，我就要离开你了
But with that, I'm leaving you
我很快就会在下一个视频中见到你。
and I see you soon in the next video.